[
  {
    "question":
      "Do I need the traditional clothing (Gi or Kimono) to train Brazilian Jiu Jitsu?",
    "answer":
      "To start with, you do not need a Gi. You can simply train in shorts and a t-shirt. When you get better, you will both want and have to start training in a Gi (except in NoGi). The Gi is essential since much of the training involves grabbing the Gi and you use the Gi for a lot of techniques in BJJ."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is NoGi Jiu Jitsu?",
    "answer":
      "NoGi is Jiu Jitsu without a Gi. People train NoGi in shorts or tight long pants and tight shirts, long- or short sleeved. In summer, we also have NoGi classes"
  },
  {
    "question": "What color of Gi should I buy?",
    "answer":
      "It does not matter. Most BJJ Gis are white, black or blue but all colors are allowed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is the Gi expensive?",
    "answer": "You can get Gis from 100 Euros and up."
  },
  {
    "question": "How do I clean the Jiu Jitsu Gi?",
    "answer":
      "You wash it on low temperatures so it does not shrink too much. If the BJJ Gi is not washed immediately after training, it can start to smell and the smell can stay in the Gi even if you wash it. Then it´s good to get a disinfection liquid to put in your washing machine along with the washing detergent."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is open mat?",
    "answer":
      "Open mat is when there is no scheduled training by a coach but people show up to the gym to grapple"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long will it take to get a black belt in Jiu Jitsu?",
    "answer":
      "First you have to get a blue, purple and a brown belt so it´s a long journey to the black belt in BJJ."
  },
  {
    "question":
      "When will I be able to defend myself if I start training BJJ today?",
    "answer":
      "Brazilian Jiu Jitsu is an excellent self defense and even after a few weeks, you will be in a better position to defend yourself than before."
  },
  {
    "question": "When can I start training BJJ?",
    "answer":
      "You can start at any time. Simply come to one of our BJJ classes and meet the coach. You won´t regret it."
  },
  {
    "question":
      "Do I need to do anything before I come to the first BJJ training?",
    "answer":
      "Simply bring your shorts and t-shirt and please cut your fingernails and toenails."
  },
  {
    "question":
      "How much does it cost to train Brazilian Jiu Jitsu at your gym in Brussels?",
    "answer": "You can check our fee plans."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I or should I do BJJ private classes?",
    "answer":
      "If you want to improve faster or if you have a difficult scheduled to fit in our collective classes, or if you prefer an one to one class you can take private classes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Is Brazilian Jiu Jitsu also for girls/women?",
    "answer":
      "Absoloutely! There are many girls training in our gym and training BJJ makes most girls and women more self confident and in a better condition to defend themselves."
  },
  {
    "question":
      "I don´t like to get punched or kicked, is BJJ then suitable for me?",
    "answer":
      "Yes, we don´t kick or punch in BJJ. We do however incorporate that threat into our training so that you are able to defend yourself against kicks and punches without using it yourself."
  }
]